<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>setup on</title><link>https://amethyst.bencuan.me/tags/setup/</link><description>Recent content in setup on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://amethyst.bencuan.me/tags/setup/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Setup</title><link>https://amethyst.bencuan.me/setup/setup/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://amethyst.bencuan.me/setup/setup/</guid><description>Getting Started # Setting up Amethyst requires a basic understanding of git. If you are unfamiliar, this resource is a great place to start!
Forking # A fork is a copy of a repository. Forking a repository allows you to freely experiment with changes without affecting the original project.
Navigate to the GitHub repository for the Amethyst project:
📁 Amethyst Repository
Then, Fork the repository into your own GitHub account.</description></item><item><title>Editing Content</title><link>https://amethyst.bencuan.me/setup/editing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://amethyst.bencuan.me/setup/editing/</guid><description>Editing # Amethyst runs on top of Hugo so all notes are written in Markdown.
Folder Structure # Here&amp;rsquo;s a rough overview of what&amp;rsquo;s what.
All notes you want to publish should go in the /content folder. To make edits, you can open any of the files and make changes directly and save it. You can organize content into any subfolder you&amp;rsquo;d like.
To edit the main home page, open /content/_index.</description></item><item><title>Obsidian Vault Integration</title><link>https://amethyst.bencuan.me/setup/obsidian/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://amethyst.bencuan.me/setup/obsidian/</guid><description>Setup # Obsidian is the preferred way to use Amethyst. You can either create a new Obsidian Vault or link one that your already have.
New Vault # If you don&amp;rsquo;t have an existing Vault, download Obsidian and create a new Vault in the /content folder that you created and cloned during the setup step.
Linking an existing Vault (simple) # The easiest way to use an existing Vault is to copy all of your files (directory and hierarchies intact) into the /content folder.</description></item><item><title>Preview Changes</title><link>https://amethyst.bencuan.me/setup/preview-changes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://amethyst.bencuan.me/setup/preview-changes/</guid><description>If you&amp;rsquo;d like to preview what your site looks like before deploying it to the internet, the following instructions guide you through installing the proper dependencies to run it locally.
Install hugo-obsidian # This step will generate the list of backlinks for Hugo to parse. Ensure you have Go (&amp;gt;= 1.16) installed.
# Install and link `hugo-obsidian` locally go install github.com/jackyzha0/hugo-obsidian@latest If you are running into an error saying that command not found: hugo-obsidian, make sure you set your GOPATH correctly!</description></item><item><title>Customization</title><link>https://amethyst.bencuan.me/setup/config/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://amethyst.bencuan.me/setup/config/</guid><description>Configuration # Amethyst is designed to be extremely configurable. You can find the bulk of the configuration scattered throughout the repository depending on how in-depth you&amp;rsquo;d like to get.
The majority of configuration can be found under config.yaml. An example, with descriptions for each setting, can be found here.
Code Block Titles # To add code block titles with Amethyst:
Ensure that code block titles are enabled in the configuration:</description></item><item><title>Deploying Amethyst to the Web</title><link>https://amethyst.bencuan.me/setup/hosting/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://amethyst.bencuan.me/setup/hosting/</guid><description>Hosting on GitHub Pages # Amethyst is designed to be effortless to deploy. If you forked and cloned Amethyst directly from the repository, everything should already be good to go! Follow the steps below.
Enable GitHub Actions # By default, GitHub disables workflows from running automatically on Forked Repostories. Head to the &amp;lsquo;Actions&amp;rsquo; tab of your forked repository and Enable Workflows to setup deploying your site!
Enable GitHub Actions</description></item></channel></rss>